<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Roman Matvienko</title><link>https://rmatv.github.io/en/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Roman Matvienko</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 23:25:05 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rmatv.github.io/en/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Yellow Card No. 1</title><link>https://rmatv.github.io/en/2025/10/booking/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 23:25:05 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://rmatv.github.io/en/2025/10/booking/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Yellow and red cards were used to caution and send off players for the
first time at the 1970 World Cup in Mexico.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;West German referee Kurt Tschenscher showed the very first yellow card in
football history in the 30th minute of the opening match, &lt;a href="https://fbref.com/en/matches/ca04761f/Mexico-Soviet-Union-May-31-1970-World-Cup"&gt;Mexico v
USSR&lt;/a&gt;,
to Soviet player Kakhi Asatiani for a foul on Gustavo Peña. The second and
third yellow cards in football history also went to Soviet players — Givi
Nodia and Evgeny Lovchev — in the 31st and 34th minutes respectively.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Northern suffering (#2): Kitchee v North District</title><link>https://rmatv.github.io/en/2025/10/north-02/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 06:11:32 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://rmatv.github.io/en/2025/10/north-02/</guid><description>&lt;figure style="width:95%;height:auto"&gt;
 &lt;img
 src="https://rmatv.github.io/images/20251026_mongkok.webp"
 alt="Kitchee v North District, the kick-off"
 width="560px" height="auto"
 loading="lazy" decoding="async"&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Sunday, I attended the sixth round of the Hong Kong Premier League —
Kitchee vs. North District in Mong Kok. The match ended in a lively 3–3
draw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kitchee are the most decorated of the current Premier League clubs. Founded
in 1931, they’ve won the Hong Kong championship twelve times — more than
anyone except South China (now playing in the First Division with 41
titles). In the last two seasons, Kitchee finished fourth, well below their
ambitions. So North District were clear underdogs.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Northern suffering (#1): Kowloon City v North District</title><link>https://rmatv.github.io/en/2025/10/north-01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 10:16:08 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://rmatv.github.io/en/2025/10/north-01/</guid><description>&lt;figure style="width:95%;height:auto"&gt;
 &lt;img src="https://rmatv.github.io/images/20251019_shamshuipo.webp"
 alt="Kowloon City v North District before kick off"
 width="560px" height="auto"
 loading="lazy" decoding="async"&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I attended the Hong Kong Premier League fifth-round match between
Kowloon City and North District at Sham Shui Po. The game ended in a 2–2
draw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Sheung Shui side took an early advantage with aggressive pressing in
the attacking third. Kowloon players frequently misplaced passes in their
own half. However, it was Kowloon who opened the scoring in the 18th
minute, punishing the opposition for committing too many players forward.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Fish</title><link>https://rmatv.github.io/en/2025/07/channa/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 00:31:47 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://rmatv.github.io/en/2025/07/channa/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Last night I came across a &lt;em&gt;fish&lt;/em&gt; on the footpath near my house. Over the
past year living here, I’ve run into (and tried not to step on) countless
snails, toads, and lizards. People have warned me about snakes, but I
haven’t seen one yet. And I have never expected to encounter a
&lt;em&gt;fish&lt;/em&gt; — fish inhabit bodies of water, and paths are not part of
those. And yet, there it was: a fish, lying in the middle of the path.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Choose to lose</title><link>https://rmatv.github.io/en/2025/06/choose-to-lose/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 06:43:03 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://rmatv.github.io/en/2025/06/choose-to-lose/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;14 June saw the final matchday in the Second Russia football league
(Division A). Trailing 2-1 at home to Mashuk-KMV, FC Chelyabinsk &lt;a href="https://vk.com/video-139174916_456244374?t=2h4m5s"&gt;spent the
final minute of the match passing the ball in their own
half&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
 &lt;video 
 controls preload="metadata"
 poster="/posters/20250614_chl_msh.webp"
 style="max-width:100%;height:auto;"&gt;
 &lt;source src="https://rmatv.github.io/video/20250614_chl_msh.mp4" type="video/mp4"&gt;
 Your browser does not support video tag.
 &lt;/video&gt;
 &lt;figcaption&gt;
 Fragment from the 
 &lt;a href="https://vk.com/video-139174916_456244374"&gt;
 official broadcast&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt; 
 Video used for non-commercial purposes to illustrate the discussion.
 &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps it was the imperfections in the league rules that caused
FC Chelyabinsk to choose to lose rather than attempt to equalise.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Pedant's note</title><link>https://rmatv.github.io/en/2020/09/risse/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 01:02:10 +0400</pubDate><guid>https://rmatv.github.io/en/2020/09/risse/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I came across a curious inaccuracy in Eric Dunning&amp;rsquo;s texts on the origins
of the sociology of sport. Dunning repeatedly refers to Heinz Risse, the
author of what appears to be the first monograph to feature the phrase
&amp;lsquo;sociology of sport&amp;rsquo; in the title (&lt;em&gt;Sociologie des Sports&lt;/em&gt;, 1921), as
a student of Theodor Adorno.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adorno supervised&lt;/strong&gt; the work on sport of Heinz Risse whose &lt;em&gt;Soziologie
des Sports&lt;/em&gt; (1921) was, so far as I know, the first time that this
subdiscipline was explicitly named. Adorno also supervised the work
of Bero Rigauer which resulted in &lt;em&gt;Sport und Arbeit&lt;/em&gt; (Sport and
Work) (1969).&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>