<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>North_district on Roman Matvienko</title><link>https://rmatv.github.io/en/tags/north_district/</link><description>Recent content in North_district on Roman Matvienko</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 15:37:14 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rmatv.github.io/en/tags/north_district/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Northern Suffering (#6): Eastern vs North District</title><link>https://rmatv.github.io/en/2026/01/north-06/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 15:37:14 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://rmatv.github.io/en/2026/01/north-06/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://rmatv.github.io/images/20260118_eastern.webp" alt="Eastern vs North District: after kickoff"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday I attended the Premier League match between Eastern and North District at Mong Kok Stadium.
The visitors won 4–1.
Goals and highlights can be watched in the &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/v1YINFSr6wU"&gt;onTV Sports review&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eastern are the oldest&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; of the current Premier League participants.
The club have been champions of Hong Kong five times:
four times before the establishment of the Premier League (1955–56, 1992–93, 1993–94, 1994–95) and once after (2015–16).
Eastern have also won the FA Cup seven times, including the last two editions of the tournament.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Northern Suffering (#5): North District vs Kowloon City</title><link>https://rmatv.github.io/en/2026/01/north-05/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 22:44:03 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://rmatv.github.io/en/2026/01/north-05/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;On Saturday I attended the Premier League match between North District and Kowloon City at North District Sports Ground.
The hosts earned a comeback victory, 2–1.
Goals and highlights are available in the &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/m3P1d0ttg3c"&gt;onTV sports&lt;/a&gt; recap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the two months since the &lt;a href="https://rmatv.github.io/en/2025/11/north-04/"&gt;previous entry&lt;/a&gt;, North District have played several matches.
On December 4, the Sheung Shui side drew 1–1 with Tai Po.
The match took place a week after the horrific fire in Tai Po that claimed, &lt;a href="https://hongkongfp.com/2026/01/15/breaking-tai-po-fire-death-toll-rises-to-168-following-forensic-analysis-all-bodies-identified/"&gt;according to the latest figures&lt;/a&gt;, 168 lives.
I attended that game, but have never been in the right mood to write about it.
North District conceded in the second half and equalised in the very first attack after the restart.
A week later, North District lost at home to Kitchee, 1–2.
I did not attend that match because I was teaching that day at the Moscow School.
On December 21, North District also beat Southern District 3–1 in the FA Cup.
I missed that match for no particularly good reason.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Northern Suffering (#4): Lee Man – North District</title><link>https://rmatv.github.io/en/2025/11/north-04/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 07:01:53 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://rmatv.github.io/en/2025/11/north-04/</guid><description>&lt;figure style="width:95%;height:auto"&gt;
 &lt;img src="https://rmatv.github.io/images/20251123_mongkok.webp"
 alt="Lee Man – North District, after the kick-off"
 width="560px" height="auto"
 loading="lazy" decoding="async"&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I attended Lee Man – North District in the ninth round of the
Premier League at Mong Kok Stadium – the very same ground that hosted &lt;a href="https://rmatv.github.io/en/2025/10/north-02/"&gt;the
match against Kitchee&lt;/a&gt;. It finished as a 2–2 draw.
You can watch the goals and key moments in the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=n7U7es_ZfS8"&gt;onTV Sports
highlights&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lee Man were founded in 2017. The club have never played in the lower Hong
Kong leagues because the owners bought them a Premier League place from the
outset. In 2023–24 they won the league for the first time, and in 2022–23
and 2024–25 they finished runners-up. Once again, North District arrived as
underdogs – all the more so given that a week earlier the teams had met in
the League Cup, where North District lost 1–2 in extra time (I wasn’t at
that match).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Northern suffering (#3): North District v Southern District</title><link>https://rmatv.github.io/en/2025/11/north-03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 02:11:31 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://rmatv.github.io/en/2025/11/north-03/</guid><description>&lt;figure style="width:95%;height:auto"&gt;
 &lt;img src="https://rmatv.github.io/images/20251102_northdistrict.webp"
 alt="North District v Southern District, kick-off"
 width="560px" height="auto"
 loading="lazy" decoding="async"&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I attended the Premier League Round 7 match between North
District and Southern District. North District came from behind to win 2–1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Southern District had finished fifth in each of the past three seasons, but
this year the team from Aberdeen started poorly — five points from five
games. I expected a laboured, low-scoring game, and that’s exactly what it
turned out to be.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Northern suffering (#2): Kitchee v North District</title><link>https://rmatv.github.io/en/2025/10/north-02/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 06:11:32 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://rmatv.github.io/en/2025/10/north-02/</guid><description>&lt;figure style="width:95%;height:auto"&gt;
 &lt;img
 src="https://rmatv.github.io/images/20251026_mongkok.webp"
 alt="Kitchee v North District, the kick-off"
 width="560px" height="auto"
 loading="lazy" decoding="async"&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Sunday, I attended the sixth round of the Hong Kong Premier League —
Kitchee vs. North District in Mong Kok. The match ended in a lively 3–3
draw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kitchee are the most decorated of the current Premier League clubs. Founded
in 1931, they’ve won the Hong Kong championship twelve times — more than
anyone except South China (now playing in the First Division with 41
titles). In the last two seasons, Kitchee finished fourth, well below their
ambitions. So North District were clear underdogs.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Northern suffering (#1): Kowloon City v North District</title><link>https://rmatv.github.io/en/2025/10/north-01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 10:16:08 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://rmatv.github.io/en/2025/10/north-01/</guid><description>&lt;figure style="width:95%;height:auto"&gt;
 &lt;img src="https://rmatv.github.io/images/20251019_shamshuipo.webp"
 alt="Kowloon City v North District before kick off"
 width="560px" height="auto"
 loading="lazy" decoding="async"&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I attended the Hong Kong Premier League fifth-round match between
Kowloon City and North District at Sham Shui Po. The game ended in a 2–2
draw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Sheung Shui side took an early advantage with aggressive pressing in
the attacking third. Kowloon players frequently misplaced passes in their
own half. However, it was Kowloon who opened the scoring in the 18th
minute, punishing the opposition for committing too many players forward.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>